《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
在阿达玛有生之年都要由他来指挥
This will be Adama's command until the day he dies.
我们不会让他离我们而去
And we are not going to let him die.
长官  我们在科波上的人怎么办
GAETA: Sir, what about our people on the surface of Kobol?
如果他们还活着就要等等了
TIGH: If they're still alive, they'll have to wait.
中尉  我认为在我们撤退之前要再检查一遍补给
El-tee, I think we should double-check the supplies before we bug out.
没时间了  上士
We don't have the time, Chief.
我可以给你打一针  但其副作用可对你不好
I could give you a shot, but you wouldn't like the side effects.
你就打吧
Just do it.
会有那么一天你不能
The time is going to come when you're not going to be able to hide
再掩盖你的处境
what you're going through.
他的肺部充满液体  如果再不注射奈法唑酮
His lungs are filling up with fluid, if he doesn't get more Serisone soon,
他就挺不住了
he's not gonna make it.
托特  你忘了医药箱  所以就要你去拿回来
Tarn, you forgot the med kit, so you've got to go back and get it.
拿一支步枪  三夹子弹  一个水壶
Take a rifle, two clips of ammo and a canteen.
太晚了  他不行了
SEELIX: It's too late. He's not gonna make it.
抱歉  上士
CRASHDOWN: I'm sorry, Chief.
科波之主
CRASHDOWN: Lords of Kobol,
带着这些勇士
take these brave men into your arms.
带着...
Take up... Take
带着我们倒下了的伙伴的灵魂...
the spirits of our fallen friends
这样他们可以在与我们挥泪分别后
so that they may share in the everlasting life
和我们分享等待世人的永生
that awaits us all beyond the veil of tears.
同心协力
So say we all.
ALL: So say we all.
没有什么在等待他们  没有永生  没有毁灭
Nothing awaits them. No eternal life. No damnation.
只有被忘却
Only oblivion.
我想是因为他们还没有见过神的模样
Because they haven't seen the face of God, I take it?
是因为他们死在了这里  死在了科波
Because they died here, on Kobol.
明白了
I see.
博士  我们走
TYROL: Doc, let's go.
该动身了
We're moving out.
博士  听到了吗?
Doc, you hear me?
要起程了
We're moving out.
听到了  上士
No, I did hear you, Chief.
只是我可不会对"博士"这个称谓作出反应 ("博士"音同"码头")
I just don't respond to the title "Doc."
码头是装货和卸货的地方
A "dock" is a platform for loading and unloading material.
我的头衔是"博士"或"副总统先生"
My title is Doctor or Mr. Vice President, if you don't mind.
你在拿着货物  不是吗?
You are loading, are you not?
中尉?
TYROL: El-tee?
中尉? 快
El-tee? Crash!
恩  上士  这就来
Yeah, Chief, I'll be right there.
没发现赛昂人
No Cylons.
你确定?
CRASHDOWN: (SIGHING) You sure?
哦
Uh-oh!
等等  树木线  两点钟方向
Wait a minute. Tree line, 2:00.
看到了  它们在干什么?
Got them. What're they doing?
看起来好象在拆船
TYROL: Looks like they're dismantling the ship.
为什么?  为什么不坐船离开这鬼地方?
CRASHDOWN: Why? Why not use it to fly the hell out of here?
不知道
I don't know.
不清楚
I can't tell.
它们把飞船拖进了树木线里
They're dragging it into the tree line.
等下  它们在造东西
Oh, wait a minute. They're building something.
上士  那是一枚...
CRASHDOWN: Chief, is that a...
导弹  它们在造导弹塔
A missile. They're building a missile battery.
我们至少知道它们为什么不追我们了
Well, at least we know why they're not chasing us.
为什么?
Why?
为什么不追了呢?
Why aren't they chasing us?
因为不必多此一举
Because they don't have to.
它们只需按兵不动  以导弹形成火力网
(SIGHING) They can just sit back, launch a missile barrage
就能把这山谷夷为平地
that'll wipe out every living thing in this valley.
下次我说我有急事在身的时候 就快点操作过渡舱
Next time I say I'm in a hurry, cycle the damn airlock faster.
你是第一天上班吗?
Is this your first day?
医生  谢天谢地  你可来了
Dr. Cottle, thank the gods you're here.
总统需要你的帮助  让道
The President needs your help. Move!
医生  医生
Doctor. Doctor!
好...
Okay.
立即报告生命指数
Let's have some vitals. Like now.
两枚子弹  9毫米口径
KIM: Two bullets, 9 mm.
这枚击穿了脾脏  另一枚划破了主动脉
This one lacerated the spleen, the other nicked the aorta.
现在我们已切除了脾脏 我们本打算修复主动脉
Now, we've removed the spleen and felt we repaired the aorta...
但在过去的几小时里 他的血压又再次下降
Over the past few hours, his B. P.'s dropped down again.
高压80  低压40 而心率渐增到130次
It's only 80/40, and his heart rate's creeping back into the 130s.
你忽略了一件事  他仍然在内出血
Well, you missed something. He's still hemorrhaging somewhere.
再不止血  他就不行了
We're gonna lose him unless we can stop that bleeding.
给我动脉血气分析  全血细胞计数 还有电凝
Get me an ABG, CBC and coags
快去设置快速气管插管
and get set up for a rapid sequence intubation.
他能挺过去吗?
Is he gonna make it?
我怎么知道?  我又没有特异功能
How should I know? I'm not a psychic.
快出去吧
Now get the hell out of here.
这里真是乱七八糟
COTTLE: It's a mess in here.
看来肠系膜动脉已经受损
Looks like the mesenteric artery may have been damaged.
3.7 的 Mac.
3.7 Mac.
见鬼  吉姆  要熟记器材的名字 我说的是3.7 Mac
Gods damn it, Kim, learn the instruments! I said a 3.7 Mac!
抱歉
KIM: Sorry.
夹住它  止血钳
Clamp it. Clamp!
卡托医生  他的血压在下降 高压60
ISHAY: Dr. Cottle, his pressure's dropping.
低压30  心率开始下落
It's 60/30. Heart rate's starting to fall.
我看他支撑不下去了
I don't think he can last much longer.
集中精神就是了
Just stay focused.
再拿些抽吸器 不然我都看不清我在干什么
Get some more suction in here so I can see what I'm doing.
上校…  指挥官怎么样了?
Colonel, how's the Commander?
什么?
What?
指挥官怎么样了?
How's the Commander?
还在手术  有什么事吗?
He's still in surgery. What's on your mind?
我得给总统拿些药
I need some medication for the President.
她已经不是总统了  卡托现在挺忙的
She's not the President anymore. Cottle's a little busy right now.
长官  她病得很重  你怎么没被关禁闭呢?
Sir, she's very ill... Why aren't you in the brig?
因为没人把我关进去?
Because no one put me in there.
这是怎么回事?
What the hell's all this?
你怎么没在禁闭室呢?
Why aren't you in the brig?
我在值班  长官  计划搜救任务
I'm on duty, sir. Planning the search and rescue mission.
搜救?  搜救谁?
Search and rescue? For who?
我们失去了一架飞船  竟没人告诉我?
We lose a plane and nobody tells me?
搜救被困在科波上的猛禽号组员  长官
For our Raptor crew down on the surface of Kobol, sir.
希蒙斯现在是高级驾驶员 他可以制定搜救计划
Simes is senior pilot now. He can plan the SAR.
你让我值班期间指挥空军  现在我在值班
You asked me to command the air group when I'm on duty, and I'm on duty,
到底要不要让我来指挥呢?
so am I in command or not?
搜救行动计划进展如何  上尉?
What's the status of the SAR, Captain?
还不清楚猛禽3号坠落的区域
APOLLO: Well, we don't know in what area Raptor 3 went down.
所以要找到它  比较现实的机会就是
So the only realistic chance we have of finding her
但愿它的应答器灾难信号灯还好用
is the hope that her transponder or disaster beacon is still functioning.
我打算派两架猛禽号
I intend to take two Raptors,
一架载着医护人员  做5次低轨道观察
one with medical personnel, and make five low-level orbits of the planet.
沃莱瑞中尉理应摧毁的…
What about that Cylon base ship
那艘赛昂基地飞船呢?
that Lieutenant Valerii supposedly destroyed?
如果她是在说谎怎么办?
What if she was lying?
雷达追踪证实基地飞船已被摧毁
Racetrack confirmed the destruction of the base ship
我也已查看了猛禽号的军事记录相机  也证实了确实如此
and I checked the gun-camera footage from the Raptors, which verifies it.
盖塔中尉  你还在迟疑什么?
Lt. Gaeta, why are you hovering about?
是新闻记者
It's the press.
新闻记者?
The press?
他们要求知道我们还要扣押他们多久
They're demanding to know how much longer we plan on holding them
以及什么时候能与他们的飞船取得联系
and when they can contact their home-ships.
他们要求?
They demand?
他们没资本要求任何事
They're in no position to demand anything.
你去告诉他们少废话
You tell them to shut their yaps.
时间一到自会联系他们
We'll get to them in due time.
打扰下  上校
DUALLA: Excuse me, Colonel.
来自【 西风号 】上的飞梭
Shuttle from the Zephyr has just requested
请求进入着陆航线
permission to enter the landing pattern.
【 西风号 】?  是的  长官
The Zephyr? Yes, sir.
很明显  12法人团体在船上 他们要求要见你
Evidently the Quorum of 12 is aboard. They're demanding to see you.
他们要求?
They demand?
指挥一艘太空堡垒可真是劳神费力啊
Demanding job, commanding a battlestar.
允许他们降落
Clear them to land.
把他们带到一间集会室 关在那里  等我有时间再去看他们
Put them in the Ward Room and hold them there until I have time to see them.
别动
Stop!
总统女士
Madam President?
她这是怎么了?
What's wrong with her?
不知道  但显然是病了
I don't know, but she's clearly sick.
这你看得出来  是吧?
You can see that, can't you?
我无能为力啊
But there's nothing I can do.
总统女士...
Madam President?
恩?
Yes.
您在里面  我能为您做些什么吗?
Can I get you anything while you're in the brig?
比利
Billy.
不  谢谢了
No, thank you.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我难以集中精神去思考
I'm finding it hard to think.
是戒断综合症
It's withdrawal.
是卡马拉吧?
The chamalla.
对
Yes.
我设法再给您多弄些
I'm trying to get you more.
快去
Go fast.
我数了一下  目前为止  它们一共送进森林里6枚导弹
I count six missiles being carried into the forest site so far.
这一切都毫无意义
It's all so pointless.
我们杀他们  他们再杀我们
We kill them, and they kill us.
然后我们再杀他们
So we kill more of them and
他们又杀我们
so they kill more of us.
到头来为了什么呢?
What's the point anymore?
你和你的种族天生就是杀人狂
You, your race invented murder.
生来就是为了狩猎  贪婪  嫉妒而杀戮的
Invented killing for sport, greed, envy...
这是人类一种真正的艺术形式
It's man's one true art form.
我看你也亲手杀过人吧
You've done some killing of your own, I think.
对  我们是你们的子女 受你们的谆谆教诲
Yes, well, we're your children. You taught us well.
为什么神要让一个孩子降临到这样的世界上呢?
Why does God want to bring a child into this kind of world, anyway?
因为即便如此… 即使发生了这一切
Because despite everything, despite all of it,
他仍想拯救你们
he still wants to offer you salvation.
我们的孩子将拯救这一切
Our child will bring that salvation,
但你必须接受扮演她父亲的这个角色
but only if you accept your role
当她的守护神
as her father and her guardian.
我还没准备好  知道吗?
I'm not ready for that, all right?
我不是一名父亲  不是一名守护神
I'm not a father, I'm not a guardian.
不是一名能够统领大家的道德领袖
I'm not a moral leader capable of leading anyone,
更别提是一名婴儿了
let alone a baby.
像个男人  盖尤斯
Be a man, Gaius.
什么?
What?
像个男人
Be a man.
不论你将成为什么人  你都是一个男人
Whatever else you are, you are that.
你挺起胸膛的时候就要到来了
The time is coming when you'll have to act like one.
等等  等等  中尉  你看
TYROL: Wait a minute, wait a minute. El-tee, check this out.
怎么了  上士?
CRASHDOWN: What do you got, Chief?
发射架以东45度 看到那树桩了吗?
45 degrees east of the launcher, you see that tree stump?
那是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is that?
看起来像是一个雷达天线
It looks like a dradis dish,
至少是赛昂人版本的雷达天线
or at least a Cylon version of a dradis dish.
大概是把飞船的前锥部位废物利用了
It's probably salvaged from the nose cone of a ship.
它们在造防空炮台
They are building an anti-aircraft battery.
防空?  为什么?
Anti-aircraft? For what?
这附近又没其他飞船
There are no other aircraft around here.
卡拉狄加会派来搜救队
The Galactica's gonna send a search and rescue team.
到那时  至少有两架猛禽机 将在坠落地点执行低空侦察任务
When they do, that's at least two Raptors doing a low pass over the crash site.
那些猛禽号上的人冒着生命危险来解救我们的时候...
When those Raptors come looking for us, risking their lives to rescue us...
赛昂人就会把他们击落下来
The Cylons will shoot them down.
7架战机待修 3架外出与巡逻机执行警戒任务
Seven birds down for repairs. Three out on picket duty with the CAP.
通讯线路繁忙  长官
Com traffic, sir.
优先信息在最上面
Priority messages are on top.
直说吧  上尉
Cut to the chase, Captain.
还要多久才能实施搜救计划
How long before you launch the SAR?
拜托  小杜  这些都标着"优先进行"
Come on, Dee, these are all marked priority.
抱歉  长官 发来时就是这样子
Sorry, sir. That's how they came in.
正在拼修305号机
I'm cannibalizing 305 for parts.
升空时间应该在...大约90分钟内
Should be up in the air in, I don't know, 90 minutes.
90分钟?  我们的人还在那该死的星球上
90 minutes? We got men down on that frakking planet!
打起精神
Get your head in the game.
做你该做的  不然就回禁闭室去
You do your job or go back to the brig.
法人代表都到集会室了吗?
Are all the members of the Quorum in the Ward Room?
12位全在  长官
All 12, sir.
我猜这件事你不能替我办了吧?
Don't suppose you want to do this for me?
从不善于在公开场合讲话  长官
Never was much at public speaking, sir.
我们为什么会在这里？  这是我想知道的
So why are we here? That's what I want to know.
到底是怎么了？ 我们会被关在…
What exactly is going on? We have been cooped up in...
劳拉·罗丝琳在这船上唆使他人发动兵变以及煽动暴乱
Laura Roslin suborned mutiny and sedition aboard this ship.
她致使一架军用设备在关键时刻遗失
She caused a key military asset to be lost at a critical moment.
阿达玛指挥官认为别无选择  只有解除她的权利
The Commander felt he had no choice but to remove her from power.
你已说过多次了
You've said that. Several times.
你好象并没听我说话  上校
Well, I... You don't seem to be listening, Colonel.
不论阿达玛是何感受  他根本无权…
It does not matter what Adama felt, he had absolutely no authority...
阿达玛心知肚明
Adama knew exactly what he was doing.
他在为宣布戒严令奠定基础
He was paving the way to declare martial law
从而实施军事独裁
and usher in a military dictatorship.
难道不是吗  上校?
Isn't that right, Colonel?
我不能替指挥官代言
I can't speak for the Commander.
他还在手术
He's still in surgery.
看起来是你在这里发号施令
Well, you seem to be giving the orders around here,
那你到底打算怎么做?
so what exactly are you planning to do?
要宣布戒严令吗?
Are you declaring martial law?
绝对不会
Absolutely not.
我知道老头子对戒严令深恶痛绝
I know for a fact that the old man hated the very idea of martial law.
他信奉自由  民主  那些好方案
He believed in freedom and democracy, and all that good stuff.
鉴于当前仍是民主时期  还有那些好方案
Well, since this is still a democracy and "all that good stuff",
我提议法人们立即与罗丝琳总统见面
I move that the Quorum demand immediate access to President Roslin.
很好  我赞成
Excellent. I second it.
在场各位表决
PORTER: All those in favor?
同意
ALL: Aye.
ZAREK: Aye.
提议通过
Motion carries.
上校  我们要求立即与总统见面
Colonel, we demand immediate access to the President.
我将认真考虑你们的"要求"
I will take your "demand" under advisement.
总统女士
ELLEN: Madam President.
显然  任何阻止那...
...anything that impedes that understanding...
总统女士
Madam President?
我不得不考虑…
I have to consider...
劳拉?
Laura?
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hi.
您没事吧?
Are you all right?
我只是下来看看是否能为您做些什么
I just came down to see if there was anything I could do for you.
能帮您做些什么吗?
Anything I can get you?
我想与我的律师见面
I would like to have a conversation with my attorney.
你能安排吗?
Could you arrange that?
恩  当然
Yeah, sure, right.
劳拉  你知道你在哪里吗?
Laura, do you know where you are?
我在监牢里
I'm in jail.
我叫什么名字?
What's my name?
我们见过面吗?
Have we met?
抱歉  不好意思
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
只是耳朵里一直嗡嗡作响  失陪
It's just the ringing. Excuse me.
嗡嗡作响?
The ringing?
这下可好
Right.
那好吧  保重
Okay, then. Take care.
天那  艾伦·泰
Oh, my gods. Ellen Tigh.
艾伦?
Ellen?
艾伦
Ellen.
科波之主…
Lords of Kobol...
发射架看来是简单的点射装置
CRASHDOWN: The launcher looks like a simple point and shoot,
无内置导航系统
no built-in guidance.
武器看来是标准的舰对舰导弹
TYROL: Ordnance appear to be standard ship-to-ship missiles.
经改装后可进行大气飞行
They're modifying it for atmospheric flight.
一名赛昂武士来回巡逻放哨
CALLY: One Cylon Centurion walks the perimeter,
在固定范围内移动
stopping at regular intervals.
控制导弹的雷达天线
BALTAR: The dradis dish that controls the missiles
通过直径测算在4.5kG的波长上
is on a 4.5 kG wavelength, judging by the diameter.
我看有两名赛昂武士在把守着
It's guarded by two Centurions, I think.
抱歉  博士 你说的是有两名赛昂武士把守?
Sorry, Doc, did you say it was guarded by two Centurions?
恩  是的
Yes, I did.
是间歇把守  还是持续把守
Okay. Is the dradis guarded continuously or intermittently?
我通过野外望远镜观察
I saw two Centurions, through the field glasses,
两名赛昂武士持续5分钟
continuously for five minutes.
都没有离开岗位
In that time they didn't leave their post.
就是说发射架附近有3名赛鬼子  天线旁有两个
So there's three toasters near the launcher, two more out by the dish.
好多赛昂人
That's a lot of Cylons.
你用过枪吗?
You ever handle a weapon?
谁  我?  没用过
Who, me? No.
我又不是士兵  克莱斯当
I'm not a soldier, Crashdown.
我尽量分配你一项最简单的任务
I'll try to give you the most simple assignment,
但会用到全部人手
but I'm going to need every man.
你该不是说我们要攻击赛昂人吧?
You're not suggesting we attack the Cylons?
在它们再杀人之前我们要替瑟纳塞斯和托特报仇
We owe it to Socinus and Tarn to take those
把这些混蛋干掉
frakkers out before they kill anyone else.
我们和它们人数相同  有奇袭的条件
We have equal numbers. We have the element of surprise.
所以我们就有主动权
Therefore we have the initiative.
可以选择进攻的时间和地点
We can attack at a time and place of our choosing.
中尉  和你单独说句话
El-tee, a word in private.
他疯了
He's crazy.
我受训可不是为了干这些事
I'm not trained for this kind of thing.
我一辈子没开过一枪
I've never fired a gun in my life.
在基本考核后  我就没开过枪
I haven't fired one since Basic.
你呢?
You?
我参军是为了挣钱上牙科学院
I just joined to pay for dental school.
对于我们来说基本地面进攻是很久以前的事了
Basic Ground Assault was a long time ago for all of us.
那些不是教官
Those aren't training officers out there,
它们是被编程的杀人机器  我们没选择的余地
they're programmed killing machines. We don't have any choice.
卡拉狄加一定会派搜救队的
Galactica will definitely be sending a search and rescue party.
只是时间问题而已 如果我们不摧毁那个发射架…
It's just a matter of time. If we don't take out that launcher...
我们无法与那样一个攻防地势相对抗
We can't go up against an armed and defended position like that.
它们两分钟内就能把我们全干掉  够了
They'll wipe us out in the first two minutes. That's enough!
上士  听好  在当前形式下 临阵不乱是很重要的
Chief, look, under the circumstances, it's important that you keep your cool.
我没慌乱啊
I don't believe I've lost my cool.
我看不是
I disagree.
我也不想攻击发射架  可那是我们的义务
Look, I don't want to attack the launcher, either, but it's our duty.
我们要替救援队着想 也要替瑟纳塞丝和托特报仇
We owe it to the rescue party, and we owe it to Socinus and Tarn.
我看不出这与瑟纳塞丝和托特有什么关系
I fail to see what this has to do with Socinus and Tarn.
也许正因为如此我才是长官  而你不是
Maybe that's why I'm an officer and you're not.
解散
Dismissed.
这次简令是用5个图示说明攻击计划
CRASHDOWN: This briefing will outline a plan of attack in five graphs.
图示一:形势
Graph 1: Situation.
我们的形势就是被困在科波上
Our situation is that we are stranded on Kobol
和5名计划…
with a group of five Cylons
要把搜救我们的飞船全部击落的赛昂人在一起
who are planning to use an AAU to destroy any SAR aircraft sent to find us.
当前没有任何友军
There are no other friendly forces present.
这图示是怎么回事?  图示二：任务
What's all this "graph" business? Graph 2: Mission.
是一条5组图示的摧毁呼叫中心的命令
It's a five paragraph order. ...to destroy the AAU...
最基本的命令工具  在候补军官学校就讲过了
It's a Basic command tool. It's taught at officer candidate school.
只是很少投入实战
It's just not usually used this literally in the field.
图示四:执行
Graph 4: Execution.
我们将从西北部进攻赛昂人的发射地点
We will assault the Cylon launch site from the northwest, using...
拜托
Oh, come on!
这是无稽之谈
This is absurd.
我们要把赛昂人的军队干掉  是吧?  我们?看看我们
What, we're taking on the Cylon Army, are we? Us? Look at us.
单凭两支步枪一个水壶?
What, with two rifles and a canteen?
你疯了吗?  够了  博士
Have you lost your mind... That's enough, Doctor.
是吗?  我无意冒犯 可我们为什么老是向上坡走?
Is it? Look, no disrespect, but why are we always going uphill?
还有没有人认为这计划太他妈的疯狂了?
Does anyone else think that his plan is frakking nuts?
让我告诉什么你什么叫公平  这叫公平  我们举手表决
I'll tell you what's fair, this is fair. We'll have a show of hands.
不行绝对不行
No! Absolutely not!
现在谁觉得这不公平的…
Now everybody who thinks it's unfair...
这不是民主
This is not a democracy. Well, it's not...
听中尉指挥
The El-tee's in charge.
不准说"如果"  "还是"  "但是"
No ifs, no ands, no buts.
他让我们上  我们就上
He say we go, we go!
不容异议
There's no questions.
我们已经损失了两个人  上士
We've already lost two men, Chief!
还要再损失几个人?
How many more people are we gonna lose?
你需要坐下来马上闭嘴
You need to sit down and shut up right now.
没人敢对我说闭嘴 我是副总统
Nobody tells me to shut up. I am the Vice President...
你需要坐下来  马上闭嘴
You need to sit down and shut up, right now.
你继续简令  中尉
Your briefing, El-tee.
多谢  上士
Thank you, Chief.
图示四:我们从西北部接近赛昂人的发射地点
Graph 4: We will approach the Cylon launch site from the northwest
凭借天然地势作为掩护
using natural ground cover to mask our approach.
作战目标是操控台
Our objective is the command and control console.
一旦我们到达这个方位
Once we reach this position,
凯莉  你去左侧
Cally, you're gonna flank out to the left,
佯攻赛昂人
making a feint on the Cylon position,
但愿吸引足够时间来让我和希利克丝
hopefully drawing their fire long enough for me and Seelix
从右侧进攻摧毁控制台
to flank out to the right and get a shot at the console.
蒂罗尔  你和副总统留在1号位置
Tyrol, you and the Vice President will stay at position one,
为两侧的作战提供火力掩护
provide covering fire for both flanking maneuvers.
神赐予我机会去领悟经文中的含义...
I have been given the opportunity to perceive from the scriptures...
我相信…
In peace I believe...
这太荒谬了  听我说
This is ridiculous. Look.
很明显她需要药物
She obviously needs her medication.
我一直在和大家说…
I keep trying to tell anyone that'll listen...
听起来她像是在说先知帕蒂亚的圣轴
It sounds like she's talking about the scrolls of the Prophet Pythia.
我猜是
I suppose.
帕蒂亚预言了一位领袖的出现
Pythia foretold the rise of a leader.
一位拯救全人类的领袖
A leader who would lead all humanity to salvation.
诸神就是这么说的
So say the gods.
看来你很了解经文
You seem to know a lot about the scriptures.
我来自杰米纳
I'm from Gemenon.
我相信经文上所描述的事实
We believe in the literal truth of the scriptures.
温纳下士?  有一种…
Corporal Venner, there's
牧师经常用的药物
a drug that priests sometimes use.
叫做卡马拉汁
It's called chamalla extract.
看来这是开心的一刻了
I guess it's happy hour.
有什么可开心的?
What's happy about it?
老头子还在做手术
Yeah. The old man's still in surgery.
我这还有一群政客和新闻记者
I got a boatload of politicians and press
要求见劳拉·罗丝琳
demanding to see Laura Roslin.
让他们得偿所愿啊  恩  可不
Let them. Yeah, right.
她疯了  这我知道
She's crazy. I know.
不  真的  索尔
No, no, really, Saul.
她疯了
She's lost it.
我刚下去到禁闭室去看她
I just went down to the brig to see her.
是吗?
You did?
她完全...疯疯癫癫的了
She's completely nuts.
都不知道自己在哪里
She doesn't even know where she is anymore.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
应该让他们去看看她
You should let them see her.
媒体和法人们都让他们去看看
The press, the Quorum, all of them.
小学老师已经精神错乱了
I mean, the little school teacher's mind has gone bye-bye and the
副总统不是失踪就是死掉了
Vice President is either missing or dead.
这就使你毫无争议地成为了这艘战舰的指挥官统领整个舰队
That leaves you in unchallenged command of this ship and this fleet.
直到老头子重新站起来
Just until the old man gets back on his feet.
那是当然
Well, of course.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗 我们准备跳跃到科波了
Galactica, Apollo. We are preparing to jump to Kobol.
收到  阿波罗  你们可以进行跳跃了 祝你好运
Roger that, Apollo. You are cleared to jump. Good hunting.
多谢  卡拉狄加
Thank you, Galactica.
走去找我们的弟兄
Let's go find our people.
好  上膛  打开保险  打开瞄准镜
Okay, cock the rifle, click the safety, open the scope.
上膛  打开保险  打开瞄准镜
Cock the rifle, click the safety, open the scope.
上膛…
Cock the rifle...
你们中的一个人将与众人为敌
NO. 6: One of you will turn against the others.
在行动中吗?
During the mission?
对
Yes.
我们中的一个人会背叛大家?  对
One of us will betray the others? Yes.
在战斗中?  对
During the attack? Yes.
但如果战斗失败呢?
But if the attack fails?
你就会死掉
You'll die.
我不会死  我是神的傀儡
Not me. I am God's instrument.
神舍弃了科波
God turned his back on Kobol.
舍弃了人类以及他们所膜拜的假神
Turned his back on man and the false gods he worshipped.
发生在科波上的事并非是他的旨意
What happens on Kobol is not his will.
准备
CRASHDOWN: Saddle up.
到痛击赛鬼子的时候了
It's time to junk some toasters.
我是副长
XO.
作战信息中心  我是杜亚拉  长官
Combat. Dualla here, sir.
法人们要求见前任总统
The Quorum is demanding to see the former President.
他们态度很强硬  让卫兵很为难
They're being pretty adamant, and they're giving the sentries a hard time.
也许该让他们的要求去见鬼吧
Well, maybe we should tell them to shove their demand up their collective asses.
怎么样?
How about that?
是  长官  对卫兵下什么指令呢?
Yes, sir. I need instructions for the sentries.
他们问该作何反应
They're asking how to respond.
去告诉他们将会见到
Tell them that they are going to get to see
他们的总统大人  就这么和他们说
what has become of their precious President. You tell them that.
收到应答器信号  肯定是殖民飞船的
I got a transponder signal. Definitely Colonial.
正在进行琐定
Trying to establish a lock.
找到了
Got it.
北半球  看来像是山区
Northern hemisphere. Looks like mountainous terrain.
是一个山谷
There's a valley.
带我们离开轨道
Take us out of orbit.
给猛禽2号发信号 让他们在我们上方列队
Signal Raptor 2 to form up on us.
它们在那儿  3个全在它们该在的位置
There they are, all three of them, right where they're supposed to be.
好了  各位  我们要进攻了
All right, people. This is it. We're going in.
凯莉  从树木线到阿尔法点
Cally, you move up the tree line to point alpha.
中尉  发射架那里有5个赛昂人
Whoa, El-tee. There's five Cylons at the launcher.
什么?
What?
有些不对劲  是吧?  计划不对
Something's wrong, isn't it? Something's wrong with the plan?
小点声  没出什么差错
Quiet down, there's nothing wrong.
只是我们少算了两个赛昂人
There's just a couple Cylons that we didn't account for.
现在有7个赛昂人了 这边5个  天线那边有2个
That makes for seven Cylons, five here and two up at the dish.
你肯定天线那边就有两个守卫吗?
Are you absolutely certain about the two guards at the dish?
我看得清清楚楚
I know what I saw.
也许只有5个赛昂人
Maybe there are only five Cylons.
只是刚更改了部署
They just changed their deployment.
它们把守卫天线的两个调了过来
They brought the two that were guarding the dish down here.
现在天线毫无防备
Now the dish is unprotected.
老天  上士 那天线差不多有一俚远
God, Chief, that dish is, like, almost a klick away.
那又怎么样?  无人防备  我们可以去摧毁它
So what? It's unprotected. We can go take it out.
用不着去攻击赛昂人的军队啊
We don't have to take on the whole Cylon army.
出了什么事?
What the hell was that?
音爆
Sonic booms.
太空飞船进入高层大气
Spacecraft entering the upper atmosphere.
是搜救行动  他们来了 就在空中  上士
It's the SAR mission. They're here. They're right up there, Chief.
必须行动了  没时间再讨论了
We got to go. There's no time for discussion.
好  大家  出发  游戏开始了
All right, everyone up, move out. It's game time.
要在赛鬼子再杀人之前把它们干掉
We're taking out these toasters before they kill any more of us.
凯莉  我说了开始行动
Cally, I said move.
我不行
I can't.
什么?  这是命令
What? That's an order.
她用不着去  我们只需去摧毁天线
She doesn't have to. We could just go take out the dish!
凯莉  快去  这可不是开玩笑  快去
Cally, you have to move. Cally, this is not a joke. Go!
这不是游戏  凯莉  快去  有人还要指望我们那
This is not a game, Cally, go! We have people counting on us.
他们就在空中了  凯莉  快去
They're up there, Cally. Move!
听我说  我们还有时间摧毁天线再赶回来
Listen to me, we still have time to double back and take out the dish.
先给我闭嘴  凯莉  技师  这是命令
Shut up for a second, Cally. Cally. Specialist, you have your orders.
马上去那里  引开它们的注意力
I need you to go up there and create a distraction, now!
快  快去  中尉
CRASHDOWN: Move! Move! El-tee.
本该只有3个赛昂人的  现在却有5个了
There were only supposed to be three Cylons and now there are five.
我们怎么能干掉5个赛昂人呢?
How are we supposed to take on five Cylons?
该死的命令  该死的战争
Frak orders, frak court martial!
我们的人就在空中 我们得救他们
Our people are up there, we have to save them.
我们没时间了  快去
We don't have any time. Move!
我不行
I can't do it.
凯莉  快去  不
Cally! Move! No!
上士
Chief!
哇  哇  嗨
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hey.
放下枪  放下枪
Put it down. Put it down.
快去那里  凯莉
You are going out there, Cally.
快去那里  不然我马上让你脑袋开花
You're going out there, or I'm going to blow your brains out.
就这里 就现在
Right here, right now.
放下  中尉  慢点  别急
Put it down. Hey, El-tee, easy. Take it easy.
我数到三
I'm gonna count to three.
疯了  疯了
This is crazy, this is crazy!
一
One.
马上放下
Put it down. Right now.
天那
SEELIX: Oh, my gods!
听我说  放下你的武器
Listen to me! Drop your weapon!
二
Two.
三
Three.
撤退  撤退
TYROL: Fall back! Fall back!
快走  走走
Go! Go! Go!
快来  博士  快走
Come on, Doc! Let's go!
现在你是个男人了
Now you're a man.
预计着陆时间?
ETA?
5分钟
Five minutes.
凯莉  凯莉
SEELIX: Cally! Oh, Cally!
博士  给我火箭筒
Doc! Give me the launcher!
给我火箭筒  博士  快
Give me the launcher, Doc! Come on!
掩护我
TYROL: Cover me!
导弹下面有炮台
Missiles! There's a battery down there!
躲避  散开  散开  散开
Evasive! Break! Break! Break!
分散队型
RACETRACK: Break formation.
没有锁定  没有锁定  它们没锁定我们
No lock! No lock! They're not locking on us!
上士
CALLY: Chief!
呆在那里别动
Stay there! Stay there!
上士  上士
Chief! Chief!
不客气
You're welcome.
动物园观光的时刻到了
Viewing time at the zoo.
很高兴看到你如此尊重总统
Glad to see you hold the President in such high esteem.
会有你好瞧的  嬉皮笑脸的小子  我们走
Your day's gonna come, laughing boy. Let's go.
她在说什么？
PORTER: What is she saying?
不知道  她什么也没说
BAGOT: I don't know. She's not saying anything.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我觉得她…
I feel like she's...
好了  展出结束了 让她一个人呆会吧
All right, the show's over. Let's give her some privacy.
大家都出去吧  到集会室去
Everybody out. Let's go back to the Ward Room
咱们讨论一下接下来的事
and we'll talk about the business of how we proceed from here.
感谢各位前来
Thank you all for coming.
我要发表声明
I have a statement I'd like to make.
试图反对殖民地合法政府的军事政变
The attempted military coup against the lawful government of the Colonies
是非法和不明智的  并注定将失败
is illegal, ill-advised, and clearly doomed to failure.
我并没有辞去总统职位 同时将…
I have not resigned the presidency, and I will fight this action
行使一切权利反抗这种行为
with everything at my command.
她疯了  精神错乱了
She's crazy. She's nuts.
她以为她是先知或是什么
She thinks she's a prophet or some such nonsense.
去问她  问问她  问她  她会告诉你的
Go ahead and ask her. Ask her, she'll tell you.
听她说吧  是什么来着?  阿波罗之箭…
Just listen to her. What was it? The Arrow of Apollo
会打开阿耳特弥斯之墓什么的
will open the tomb of Artemis, or some such nonsense.
到现在为止我所做的一切都是符合逻辑的
Everything I have done is consistent, logical.
我们已经发现了科波  我们已经找到了诸神之城
We have found Kobol. We have found the city of the gods.
当我们获得神箭之后 将打开雅典娜之墓
And when we retrieve the Arrow, we will open the tomb of Athena
我们将找到到达地球的道路
and we will find the road to Earth.
总统女士  您读过帕蒂亚的圣轴吗?
Madam President, have you read the scrolls of Pythia?
仔细读了许多遍  我谦恭地相信…
Carefully and many times, and I humbly believe that
我在充当那位领袖的角色
I am fulfilling the role of the leader.
胡说八道够了  各位出去吧
Okay, enough of this nonsense. Everybody out.
我不这么想  等下  等等
I don't think so. Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
莎拉  你代表杰米纳  你比大家都更了解圣轴和…
Sarah, you represent Gemenon, you know more about the scrolls
经文 你来说一下吧
and the scriptures than anybody else here. Why don't you speak up?
圣轴上说一位不久于世的领袖将拯救我们
The scrolls tell us that a dying leader will lead us to salvation.
她不是快死了  而是疯了
She's not dying, she's crazy.
我确实快死了
I am dying.
我患有晚期乳腺癌
I have terminal breast cancer.
卡托医生会证实诊断结果
Dr. Cottle will verify the diagnosis.
还能活几个月的时间
I have a few months to live.
在这段时间里  我将带领人民脱离苦难
And in that time, I will lead the people to salvation.
这是我个人意愿
It is my sole purpose.
赞美主
Praise be to the gods.
这就是我们的救世主
Here is our salvation.
中士  是  长官
Sergeant of the Guard! Yes, sir.
把这些人带出禁闭室  护送他们回飞梭
Remove these people from the brig and escort them back to their shuttle.
谢谢你  下士
Thank you, Corporal.
感谢诸神
Thank the gods.
损失惨重  上士
It's a hell of a butcher's bill, Chief.
克莱斯当怎么死的?
How did Crashdown die?
冲锋在前
Leading the charge.
他以最光荣的形式献出了自己的生命
He gave his life in the finest tradition of the service.
恩  他是一名英雄  一直到最后
Yeah. He was a hero to the end.
我真为你感到骄傲  盖尤斯
I'm so proud of you, Gaius.
为什么?
Why?
因为我夺走了一个人的生命吗?
Because I've taken a life?
这才说明你是人类
It makes you human.
是吗?
Is it?
没有良知?
Not conscious thought,
没有诗情  画意  音乐  文学?
not poetry, or art, or music, literature?
杀戮  杀戮才是我的遗产
Murder. Murder is my heritage.
这是我该遗留给我子孙的财产吗?
Is that the lesson I'm supposed to pass on to our child?
会没事的  盖尤斯
It'll be all right, Gaius.
博士  我们走 来吧  博士  我们得走了
Hey, Doctor, let's go! Doctor, come on! We got to go!
我将充当你的良心
I'll be your conscience.
快来  博士我们该走了
APOLLO: Come on, Doctor! We got to get out of here!
他能活下来
He'll live.
什么时候能醒过来?
When will he wake up?
我了解他  大概他想醒来的时候就会醒的
Knowing him, when he damn well wants to, probably.
我把事情给你搞得一团糟  比尔
I really frakked things up for you, Bill.
发生在殖民者一号上的事件是不幸的
The events which took place aboard Colonial One are unfortunate.
劳拉·罗丝琳在军中唆使他人兵变
Laura Roslin's actions in suborning mutiny and sedition
煽动暴乱是无法容忍的
among the military could not be tolerated.
因此阿达玛指挥官别无选择
Therefore, Commander Adama was left with no choice
只能解除她的权利
other than to remove her from office.
罗丝琳女士现正舒适地在这艘船上休息
Miss Roslin is now resting comfortably aboard this ship
直到指挥官作出进一步指示
where she will remain until such time as the Commander deems otherwise.
显然  政府无法…
As it appears obvious that the government
在当前形势下继续运作
cannot function under the current circumstances,
我已决定解散12法人团体
I have decided to dissolve the Quorum of 12
此时此刻  我宣布实施戒严令
and as of this moment, I have declared martial law.
把那些人从我的船上弄出去
Get those people the hell off my ship.
是  长官
Yes, sir.